Welcome brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer where we
open up with the ten commandments that
God had written for the whole world to
keep. Brother Tenzel
and God spake all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee [snorts] out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shall
have no other gods before me. Thou not
make it to thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. For the Lord thy God, am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of
the fathers upon the children, unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless,
that take of his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days sh thou labor and do all thy work,
but the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt not
do any work. Thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, and nor
that stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
steal. Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
cover thy neighbor's house. Thou does
not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid's servant,
nor his ax, nor his ass, nor anything
that is thy neighbors. You ready? Exodus
21-17.
And may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and long
scripture questions as well as questions
of debate. We are not here to debate. We
are here to spread the true gospel of
Jesus. So please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you please keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Jerome,
>> rest in peace. Brother Tenzel,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
>> Uh, yes. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Shangquila Au jobi asks, "What does it
mean to honor your parents as adults?
Should we still have childlike mindset
when around them following their every
demand?"
>> All right. So, if you're honoring your
parents, do you still have to have a
child mindset? Guess call them.
>> Of course you don't.
What you have to do is you you respect
them. But you're grown. Grown people do
what they want to do. But that don't
mean you have to disrespect your parent.
Let's go into Matthew the 15th chapter
and read verse four.
Matthew 15 and verse 4.
For God commanded, saying, "Honor thy
father and thy and mother, and he that
cursed father or mother, let him die the
death."
So that's the whole thing in a nutshell.
You just you you don't disrespect him.
You don't holl at him. You don't swear
at them or curse them or talk bad to
them. If they want you to do something
that you don't want to do, then you have
to politely say, "No, I can't do that. I
won't do that.
is all about respect. That's what honor
is, respect. That don't mean you obey
them like a child and and and and ask
them and obey every whim. What what have
they told you to uh uh jump off a
building?
>> Nope.
>> Only honor your mother and your father
mean you respect them. Don't disrespect
them. Don't holl at them. Don't scream
at them. Don't push them around. And
like some people do, don't don't dare
put your hands on them.
>> Yes.
>> Respect them. That's all.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Skyriter asks, "What does the
what does
for the dead part mean in Leviticus 19
verse 28?" Also, is it referring to
tattooing names of dead people? Does
that mean that tattoo in general are not
sinful? And Sammy says, "Is getting her
tattoo bad?
All right. So, and Leviticus 19 was the
first script. We go ask brother Julius
shed some light.
Let's go to that, brother Tanzan. Let's
go to Leviticus the uh 19th chapter. Uh
sin is the transgression of the law. 1
John 3:4. Sin is a transgression of the
law. But when the Lord say thou shalt
not, and you do something, that's a
whole different picture. Let's go read
it. Uh because this is about personal
conduct. A lot of this is about personal
laws and personal conduct. Go ahead. Uh
because a lot of stuff times the pagans
practice these things. That's why the
Lord said, "Don't learn the ways of the
nations." Read it at verse 20. Um uh
Leviticus uh 19. Read verse one and two
first. Go ahead.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto all the congregation of the
children of Israel, and say unto them,
you shall be holy, for I, the Lord your
God, am holy."
>> Now, now read verse 28.
>> You shall not make any cutings in your
flesh for the dead.
>> For the dead.
That is what uh the pagans did. They
practiced and that's what they did. They
cut and they put prints on themselves
for the dead, sisters and brothers,
honoring false gods, honoring their
loved one, they deceased loved ones. You
don't do that. Go ahead.
>> Nor print any marks upon you. I am the
Lord.
>> Now, let me give you a perfect example.
Let's go to First Kings the 18th
chapter.
First Kings the 18th chapter.
because they got people that still
practice this. Some people call it uh
pennis uh in and when it comes to
religion. First Kings 18, read 25 and
26. First Kings 18:25.
This is in the days of Elijah.
Elijah the prophet. Read verse 25 and
26. Go ahead. And Elijah said unto the
prophet of Bael, "Choose you one bullock
for yourselves, and dress it first, for
ye are many, and call on the name of
your God, but put no fire under."
>> Go ahead.
>> And they took the bullock which was
given them, and they dressed it, and
called on the name of Bael from morning
even to noon,
>> saying, "Oh, Bael, hear us." But there
was no voice, nor any that answered. And
they leaped upon the altar which was
made.
>> Now give me verse 28. There was no come
no answer from Baal. Look what these
pagans did in honor of their God.
Because trying to call out to their God
looking for a response. What did they
do?
>> And they cried aloud and cut themselves
out of their manner with knives and
lances te till the blood cush out upon
them. Now in this case they was cutting
themselves for some pagan gods and and
people do it for different reasons but
when the book says don't cut you you
shall not cut yourself for the dead that
is your deceased loved ones. You don't
do that because a whole lot of stuff
stem from that. That's all I got.
Anybody else?
>> So is getting a tattoo bad?
Tattoos are made to be seen, but they're
made to be seen, but it's for a
different reason. It's not sin. It's for
the dead.
>> There's another uh place in there in
Deuteronomy, if somebody can find it
right quick, concerning that same thing.
>> Yeah. Um, let me see here.
>> Deuteronomy 14 and 1.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Ye are the children of the Lord your
God.
You shall not cut yourself nor make any
balders between your eyes for the dead.
>> For the what?
>> For the dead.
>> And that's what it's all about. For the
dead. Tattoos. Uh uh uh uh. You know,
you don't put if you don't if you don't
put no cut yourself or put no tattoos on
you for the dead, then uh uh uh it ain't
no sin. Then is a transgression of the
law. But the Lord said, "Don't put no t
no uh uh uh markings or t markings on
you or cut yourself for the dead and you
do it." Now that's sin because the Lord
said, "Don't do it." Right?
>> But tattoos are not sin.
>> All right,
we're going to leave it right there as
we continue to move on to our next one.
>> Moving on. Miss Wade asks, "Does ban b a
n d and zechariah 11 verse14 mean
Israel?"
>> All right. Does ban mean Israel? And
that Zechariah 11
and verse 14,
what you say, brother Jerome?
>> Um, let's go read the verse.
>> Zechariah 11:14.
>> Yeah. Then I cut a son to my other
staff, even bands, that I might break
the brotherhood between Judah and
Israel.
>> Okay, so ban in this verse is referring
to um the children of Israel. And he and
he also said in that verse, he cut
aunder
uh the staff which is called ban that he
might break the brotherhood between
Judah. And under the banner of Judah is
three tribes. Uh Judah, Benjamin, and
Levi and Israel. In this case, it's a
it's a banner that make them up, which
is nine tribes. So he he split them he
split them aunder.
Yeah. But yeah, it's it's Israel. The
children of Israel.
That That's all I got.
>> All right.
>> And that happened after that happened
after the death of Solomon.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, we hope that that answers
your question as we continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Christy Watson says, "I'm
confused regarding Deuteronomy 12 vers 5
vers 20 and vers 22." In those verses
they say that whatsoever your soul lusts
after unclean and clean they could eat.
They could not eat unclean. Correct.
>> That is correct. They could not eat
unclean. That is correct.
>> People don't pay no attention to what
they read. Go read the scripture.
>> That's that Deuteronomy 12.
And let's pick it up at that verse 15
and then 20 and 22 is a part of that
question also. Tanzel, go right ahead.
Notwithstanding, thou mayest kill and
eat flesh in all thy gates, whatsoever
thy soul lusted after, according to the
blessing of the Lord thy God, which he
have given thee, the unclean, and the
clean may eat thereof as of the ro and
as of the heart.
>> Pay attention. It said the unclean or
clean may eat that thereof. It didn't
say you may eat the clean unclean. What
is it? What it's saying is a unclean
person, a a clean person can eat of it.
>> That's right.
>> It's not saying you can eat unclean
thing. It's like I said, people don't
read. They read, but they don't pay no
attention. But they read it. Read it
again, brother.
Notwithstanding, thou mayest kill, and
eat flesh in all thy gate, whatsoever
thy soul lusted after, according to the
blessing of the Lord thy God, which he
hath given thee, the unclean and the
clean may eat thereof, as of the rogue
book, and as of the heart.
>> So we said the unclean and the clean may
eat thereof. We didn't say that you may
eat the clean and the unclean.
the clean and unclean person people
might eat their hood.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Can we go to Deuteronomy 15
and read one verse to bring in the clean
and unclean person that's written in
this statement?
Deuteronomy 15 and verse 22.
>> Thou shalt eat it within thy gates. The
unclean and the clean person shall eat
it alike as the road book and as the
heart.
All right.
So just showing there that even the
people were considered to be clean and
unclean. So that's what the guest caller
was saying about in that verse 15. Can't
break the dietary law. It is permanent.
All right. We're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Be alert as asks in 1 Samuel
2:es
1 and 10, what's the meaning of the word
horn? Does it have the same meaning in
those scriptures? 1 and 10.
>> 1 Samuel 2 verse 1 and verse 10. Tell us
a little something about that horn,
Brother Julius.
Uh,
>> let's read it. 1 Samuel 2 and 1:10. 10.
>> And Hannah prayed and said, "My heart
rejoice in the Lord. My horn is exalted
in the Lord. My mouth is enlarged over
my enemies because I rejoice in thy
salvation."
>> Now skip down to verse 10 and read it.
>> The adversaries of the Lord shall be
broken to pieces. Out of heaven shall
the thunder shall he thunder upon them.
And the Lord shall judge the ends of the
earth and he shall give strength unto
his kings and exalt the horn of his
anointing.
>> Now it depends upon Bible context and
what's said what what's being read. The
word horn has uh two uh two meanings. It
can mean power and strength. And this
right here have verse uh verse one she's
saying my horn which is her strength or
her power is exalted in the Lord. Then
it mean it can mean a king or it can
mean a a ruler but yet still power. So
read verse uh 10 again.
>> The adversaries of the Lord shall be
broken to pieces. Out of heaven shall he
thunder upon them. And the Lord shall
judge the ends of the earth
>> shall strength unto his king
>> and the horn of his anointing.
>> That's right. So it can mean strength in
this and this. So it can mean the same
thing because the the strength of Israel
is it's a metaphor. Let me give you one
more example. Let's go to uh but a horn
is also a bony protrusion out of a head
of an animal like a sheep or cattle or a
goat or the horn of a rhinoceros of the
Indian rhinoceros. It depends upon Bible
context. In these two scriptures here,
it represents strength and power. Now,
let me go one more place. Let's go to
Luke the first chapter
cuz Hannah said uh my heart rejoice in
the Lord my horn is exalted in the Lord
her strength.
Luke chapter 1 and we verse 69. Tenzel
Luke 1 and 69
when you get it brother read it.
>> And I've raised up a horn of salvation
for us in the house of his servant
David. Now that represents Jesus.
He is the horn of our salvation. So you
have to have understand uh definitions
and Bible context.
>> Right?
>> I hope that helped.
Uh, another example you could read on
your own, Daniel 7 when um when it comes
to kings, the Daniel 7 7 and 8, he's
talking about the little horn represents
the pope,
>> right?
>> So, it can represent kings, it can rep
power or it could represent the horn of
an animal depend upon Bible context and
the scripture that you gave that repres
both of those represent strength,
strength and power in the Lord.
Yes, sir. Cuz she prayed for that
manchild, Brother Julius, and the Lord
granted her petition.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered that question as we
continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Toriia Mullen asks,
"When it comes to cheating in marriage,
if a man cheats and then says, well,
she's my wife, too." Now, is this still
sin? Even if the wife he married had no
knowledge of the other woman or agreed
to this.
>> All right. Man cheats and say, "I got
two wives." Guess call her.
>> Yes, it's sick
don't mean getting married. Let's go to
Exodus the 12th chapter, read verses 16
and 17.
Exodus 12 16- 17. And in the first day
there should be a holy convocation.
>> And in the seven days,
>> Exodus 22
16-1 17. Exodus 22 16 and 17.
>> Okay.
And if and if a man entice a maid that
is not betrod and lie with her, he shall
surely endow her to be wife. If her
fatherly refute,
>> pay attention to what it said. If he lie
with a maid, just you know, a virgin or
whatever,
he said he shall surely endow her to be
his wife.
It didn't say he was married to her.
Isn't that correct? Right.
>> And he and she might not become his
wife. Read. Keep reading.
>> If a father utterly refused to give her
unto him, he shall pay money according
to the boundary of virgins.
>> So now if if lamb with her made her his
wife, how can her father say you can't
have her?
>> Right?
>> Simple as that. So, I show you what you
are if you're running around sleeping
with women. Let's go to First Corinthian
the 6th chapter. Uh uh 1 Corinthian the
uh 7th chapter. We going to read 1 2 and
skip down to nine.
Now, concerning the things whereof, he
wrote unto me, it is good for a man not
to touch a woman.
Verse N. But if they cannot contain, let
them marry. For it is better to marry
than to burn.
>> But she burn where?
In the lake of fire.
>> In lake of fire. Burn.
>> If you can't If you can't contraain your
sex drive, then get you a wife
because otherwise you you uh uh uh uh
you'll mess it up. Now, did you read
one, two, and nine?
Now go back to two, Tanzel and then skip
down to nine.
>> You missed something.
>> Nevertheless, to avoid fornication, let
every man have his own wife and let
every woman.
>> See, that's what you to avoid what?
>> Fornication.
>> Fornication,
let every man have his own wife. And
then and so you don't get become your
wife by you laying with her. You're a
fornicator.
Was that the end of two?
>> Now read the middle of two. And let
every woman have her own husband.
>> Okay. Now verse n again.
>> But if they cannot contain, let them
marry. For it is better to marry than to
burn.
>> Yep.
>> So his brother running around sleep with
women telling they become his wife, you
going to end up in the lake of fire,
partner.
Now let's skip now. Now now let's go to
first back up to first Corinthian the
6th chapter and verse 18 6 and 18.
>> Believe fornication.
Every sin that a man do of is without
the body. But he that committeth
fornication
sin against his own body.
>> Now to flee fornication. Every sin you
commit is without the body. But anybody
that commits fornication sins against
his own body cuz you going to end up
burning in the lake of fire.
That's all I have to say.
>> And brother
>> and guess caller. And that's with one
wife, not with multiple wives. You only
have one wife.
>> You get one wife and everybody else
you're fornicating with.
>> Simple as that.
All right, take heed as we move on to
our next question.
>> Next one. Be alert as in Zephaniah 1
verse7, is this scripture related to the
parable as Luke 14 verse 16.
>> All right. In the book of Zephaniah 1
and7, a little book Nah HC and then
Zephaniah. Brother Jerome.
No, they they different. But let's go um
read them. Um Zephaniah 1:7
and then the Luke 14-16.
Zephaniah 1 and7.
>> Yeah.
The word of the Lord which came unto
Zephaniah the son of Kushi the son of
Galiah the son of Amoriah the son of
Hezekiah in the days of Josiah the son
of Amma king of Judah
>> that's Luke one that's Zephaniah
>> you wrong book bro
>> Ze Zephaniah
chapter 1 verse 7
>> Zephaniah Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Right after Habca, right?
>> Yep. One and seven.
>> Okay.
That that don't start up like that. The
word of the Lord came to Zephaniah.
>> It it says uh hold thy peace at the
presence of the Lord God. For the day of
the Lord is at hand. For the Lord has
prepared a sacrifice. He has bid his
guest.
>> Yeah.
>> Zephaniah.
>> Yeah. That's
>> Were you in Zechariah?
>> Huh?
>> No, I thought it was a Zephaniah, man.
Part of the body.
>> Okay. Well, we uh we just had Julius
read it. So, okay.
>> Go ahead uh with your explanation,
Congress.
>> Yeah. So, that that Zephaniah 1 and7
that's dealing with the uh destruction
of the wicked. uh when when the Lord
returns. So uh can you read that verse 8
and then skip to verse 15 and 16?
And it shall come to pass in the day of
the Lord's sacrifice that I will punish
the princes and the king's children and
all such as are clothed with strange
apparel. and verse 15 and 16.
>> Okay,
>> that day is a day of wrath, a day of
trouble and distress, a day of wastess
and desolation, a day of darkness and
glooiness, a day of clouds and thick
darkness, a day of the trumpet and alarm
against the fifth cities and against the
high towers.
>> Now let let's tie that to the third
chapter and read verse 89.
Zephaniah 3.
>> Yep.
>> And verse 8.
Therefore, wait ye upon me, sayeth the
Lord, until the day that I rise up to
the prey. For my determination is to
gather the nations, that I may assemble
the kingdoms to pour upon them my
ignation, even all my fierce anger. For
all the earth shall be devoured with the
fire of my jealousy.
For then will I turn to the people of
pure language that they may all call
upon the name of the Lord to serve him
with one consent.
>> Yeah. So that's that that's Zephaniah
talking about the Lord destroying the
wicked when he returned. Now let's let's
go to that uh Luke 14 and 16.
>> Luke 14 and 16. All right, brother
Tanzel. I know you're back with us.
>> No, I was there man. I just read the
first verse. That's why I said heck uh
uh Zephaniah is right before.
I accidentally read the first verse.
>> Okay.
>> You know what I'm saying? So, you know,
it's all good.
>> Where you going, Jerome?
>> Um Luke 14:E1 16.
>> Luke 14:16.
Then said he unto him, "A certain man
made a great supper and bathed many
>> and a servant at supper."
>> That's good. This verse 16.
>> Yeah. So that's that's dealing with the
uh
um the Passover when the Lord is going
to uh eat it again. Uh he said, "I ain't
going to eat it again no more until I
eat it a new in my father's kingdom."
So they different. All right. So can you
um read that verse above it? Read verse
15.
>> And when one of them that sat at me with
him heard these things, he said unto
him, "Blessed is he that shall eat bread
in the kingdom of God."
>> Yeah. And the kingdom of God in this
case is talking about the father's
kingdom. So when he when Jesus said, "I
ain't going to eat this supper until I
eat it again in my father's kingdom." He
said that in in Luke 22.
Luke 22 verse 15 and 16.
Go ahead when you get it.
>> Luke 22:15
16. And he said unto them, with desire,
I have desired to eat this Passover with
you before I suffer. For I say unto you,
I would not anymore eat thereof until it
be fulfilled in the kingdom of God.
>> Yeah, that's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on,
>> moving on. Zion asked in Hebrews 9 verse
27, does that mean as soon as
someone dies, they get their judgment?
>> Oh, Dre, we really need some light on
this question, brother. Go right ahead.
>> No, it does not mean that. Let's go to
Luke uh Hebrews 9 and read verse 27.
Go ahead when you get there, brother.
>> And as it is appointed unto men once to
die, but after this the judgment.
>> Read verse 28.
>> So Christ was once offered to bear the
sins of many. And unto them that look
for him shall he appear the second time
without sin unto salvation.
>> That's right. So the second time he
appear,
it will be unto salvation. It says right
there, but this onto man once to die,
but afterward the judgment. It just
don't say how long afterwards. Let's go
over to uh Revelation 20 now. Revelation
and pick it up at verse 4. Revelation 20
and 4. When you get there, read that,
brother.
>> And I saw thrones, and they that sat
upon them, and judgment was given unto
them. And I saw the souls of them that
were beheaded for the witness of Jesus,
and for the word of God, and which had
not worshiped the beast, neither his
image, neither had received his mark
upon their forehead or in their hands.
And they lived and reigned with Christ a
thousand years.
>> Go ahead.
>> But the rest of the dead live not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection.
>> So this is the first resurrection here.
But read on. Read verse six.
>> Blessed and holy is he that hath part in
the first resurrection. On such the
second death hath no power, but they
shall be priests of God and of Christ
and shall reign with him a thousand
years.
>> So they will be in the millennial and
the thousand year period as immortals
and they will reign with Christ a
thousand years. Now skip down and read
verse 11. Verse 11, go ahead.
>> And I saw a great white throne, and him
that sat on it,
>> from whose face the earth and the
heavens fled away, and there was found
no place for them.
>> Yes.
>> And I saw the dead small and great stand
before God, and the books were open, and
another book was open, which is the book
of life. M
>> and the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works.
>> So this is the great white throne
judgment. But go ahead.
>> And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it. And death and hell delivered up
the dead which were in them. And they
were judged every man according to their
works.
>> Go ahead.
>> And death and hell were cast into the
lake of fire. This is the second death.
>> Go ahead. And whosoever was not found
written in the book of life was cast
into the lake of fire.
>> So immediately after you die, you go
into the grave until the resurrection.
But let's go to one more place. Let's go
to 1 Corinthians 15 and we going to
start at verse 21 there.
1 Corinthians 15 and 21. Go ahead,
brother. When you get it. For since by
man came death, by man came also the
resurrection of the dead.
>> For as in Adam all die, but even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
>> Yes.
>> But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits, afterwards they that
are Christ at his coming.
[clears throat]
>> At his coming, that's when they will be
made alive. At his coming. Go ahead.
Then cometh the end when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the father, when he shall have put down
all rule and all authority and power.
>> Go ahead.
>> For he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet. The last enemy
that shall be destroyed is death.
>> Now read verse 28 and that will be it.
Go ahead.
And when all things shall be subdued
unto him, then shall the Son also
himself be subject unto him that put all
things unto him, that God may be all in
all.
>> That's right. So at that time, God is
going to be all in all and God and there
will be just God.
God's. So until that time, we in the
grave until the resurrection.
And that's all I got.
>> Yeah. Like you say, Dre, the Lord say,
"My reward is with me.
>> Give to every man."
>> That's right.
>> According as his work shall be. Thank
you, brother. Hope that answers your
question. Sister Deborah, time check as
we proceed to our next one.
>> Yes, the time is 8:07.
CMBB Haluosski
asks, "If Adam and Eve never sinned in
the Garden of Eden, would mankind even
be here? Would they have still
procreated if they didn't sin?"
>> All right, hypothetical here. If they
had not sinned, Brother Julius,
>> the answer is yes.
If Adam and Eve had never sinned in the
Garden of Eden, would they would mankind
even be here? The answer is yes, because
that was the plan of God. That was the
plan and purpose of God. Would they have
still procreated if they didn't sin?
Yes, because it's still the plan of God.
Because remember uh before man's sin
they before man's before man when God
created man before he sinned he was
already here got man from the dust of
the ground. Let me show you some how he
did it. Let's go to Genesis chapter one
because God wants to add to his family.
That is the purpose of us flesh and
blood being here so we could process or
graduate from the flesh into spirit
beings. Go ahead at 20 uh Genesis 1-26.
And God said, "Let us make man in our
image, after our likeness, and let them
have dominion over the fish of the sea,
and over the fowls of the air, and over
the cattle, and over all the earth, and
over every creeping thing that creepeth
upon the earth."
>> So the plan of God was already in
intact.
Let us make man in our image, after our
likeness. Now, would they still
procreate? They are that was the plan.
Verse 28, read it.
>> And God blessed them. And God said unto
them, "Be fruitful and multiply, and
replenish the earth, and subdue it, and
have dominion over the fish of the sea,
and over the fowls of the air, and over
every living thing that moveth upon the
earth." So now, why did God create this
earth with the plan of God been
frustrated? No. Let's go to Isaiah 45,
my last place. Isaiah 45.
Isaiah 45.
Because God don't do anything in vain,
it will fulfill the purpose that he set
forth for it to do.
Isaiah 45:18 T. When you get it, read
it.
>> For thus sayeth the Lord that created
the heavens, God himself that formed the
earth and made it. He have established
it. He created it not in vain. He formed
it to be inhabited. I am the Lord and
there is none else.
>> So the plan was already set. He created
the earth. Everything he did in Genesis
chapter one was to furbish this earth
for the creation of man.
Instruct the man. And then eventually if
man obeyed if if man had obeyed God, sin
would not be here. Death would not be
here. But the plan of God was to create
God. And it was a process and it's still
a process and it's going to happen. So
therefore the answer is to your question
is yes and yes
>> because really the [clears throat]
simplicity is before man sin God had
already commanded him to be fruitful and
multiply and replenish the earth.
>> Yes sir.
>> Yeah. So would have still been some
would have been pre procreation going on
minus the sin.
>> Multiply means to multiply means to
create a great number. That's it.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Charles Tumer asks, "Is it a
sin to join the military?"
>> Yes, caller. Is it a sin to join the
army, navy, air force, marines, coast
guard, etc.
You know,
I want you to go and read one thing
going to first John 3 and 4. Yes, sir.
>> 1 John 3 and 4.
Whosoever committh sin transgresseth
also the law, for sin is the
transgression of the law.
So I didn't see no way to listen in the
law when it said, "Thou shalt not go
into the military."
>> So no, it's not a sin.
>> Nope. Military going in can still save
some lives. All right, we'll leave that
there as we continue to move on to our
next question.
>> Next one. New West asks, "How do we
combat evil thoughts?"
>> Brother Dre, how do we combat evil
thoughts with this evil mind we have
sometimes?
>> Yeah. Let's go over to uh Romans 7.
Romans 7. We're going to start at verse
18 there. Romans 7 and 18. And we're
gonna skip Romans 7 and 18. Go ahead,
brother Tanzel.
>> For I know that in me that is in my
flesh dwelleth no good thing. For to
will is present with me, but how to
perform that which is good, I find not.
>> So that's the thing that's going on in
the flesh. And you want to know how you
combat that? because you might have the
will to do what's right, but then that
flesh is fighting against you. Skip down
to verse 21.
>> I find then a law that when I would do
good, evil is present with me.
>> Go ahead.
>> For I delight in the law of God after
the inward man.
But I see another law in my members
waring against the law of my mind and
bringing me into captivity to the law of
sin which is in my members.
>> So that that war starts off in the mind.
That's where the wars start at.
And if you delight in the law of God
after the inward man, then you don't
feed
those thoughts that come into your mind.
But go ahead.
>> Oh wretched man that I am. Who shall
deliver me from the body of this death?
>> I thank God through Jesus Christ our
Lord. So then with the mind I myself
serve the law of God, but with the flesh
the law of sin. So, it's that war, the
flesh against the spirit. And that
spirit is the word of God, the law of
God. Now, go right over to the eth
chapter of Romans and pick it up at
verse five, 8 and five. Go ahead.
>> But they that are after the flesh do
mind the things of the flesh.
>> But they that are after the spirit the
things of the spirit.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> For to be carnal minded is death. But to
be spiritually minded is life and peace.
>> So if you feed in the flesh and and your
carnal mind, to be carnally minded is
death, but to be spiritually minded is
life and peace. But this spiritual mind
is talking about the law of God being in
your mind. Read the next verse.
Because the carnal mind is empty against
God. For it is not subject to the law of
God. Neither indeed can be.
>> Go ahead.
>> So then they that are in the flesh
cannot please God.
>> So the carnal mind is not subject to the
law of God, but the spiritual mind is.
Now I got one more place on how you
fight that. Let's go to second
Corinthians the 10th chapter. 2
Corinthians 10.
2 Corinthians 10.
I want you to uh pick it up at verse
three because we in this flesh, but you
have to put on the spirit of God. And
this is what it's going to tell you to
do. Go ahead.
>> But though we walk in the flesh, we do
not war after the flesh. Mhm.
>> The weapons of our warfare are not
carnal, but mighty through God to the
pulling downs of strongholds.
>> Notice that it says it's mighty through
God to the pulling down of strongholds.
Meaning that you have to submit to the
word of God.
>> That's right.
>> Because if you don't and you feed that
flesh, you gonna be in trouble. Read the
next verse. Go ahead. casting down
imaginations and every high thing that
exalt itself against the knowledge of
God
>> and bringing into captivity every
thought to the obedience [clears throat]
of Christ.
That's it. That's the answer. You got to
cast down them imaginations and every
high thing that exalt itself against the
knowledge of God and bring into
captivity every thought that come into
your mind to the obedience of Christ.
>> And when you read Ephesians 6, it tell
you to put on the whole armor. Ephesians
6:10-17
on your own.
And they tell you to have on the sword
of the spirit, which is the word of God.
>> So you keep that and you abide in it,
you all right.
>> But if you don't, you in trouble. That's
all I got.
>> Yeah. Keep them prayers going up.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Thank you, brother. Some good
light there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Katie Trezac asks, "What is
the difference between teaching and
edifying in regards to women?"
We are not to teach men, but how do
women speak boldly of him when a man is
unlearned or rely on his own
understanding?
>> All right. I'd like to open this
question here up to the panel because
you can correct a man if he's wrong in
this word of God. Open to the panel.
Let's go to uh Joel 2. Joel 2. That's
one place
amongst many. Joel 2. And let's pick it
up at that verse uh 28. Tanzel Joel 2
and 28.
27 and 28. Go ahead.
>> And you shall know that I am in the
midst of Israel, and that I am the Lord
your God, and none else, and my people
shall never be ashamed.
>> And it shall come to pass afterward that
I will pour out my spirit upon all
flesh. And your sons and your daughters
shall prophesize, the old men shall
dream dreams, the young men shall see
visions.
Mhm.
>> 29 and then open to the panel.
>> And also upon the servants and upon the
handmaids in those days will I pour out
my spirit.
>> All right panel. So the difference they
want to know too between teaching and
and edifying. Julius come off mute
please.
>> Teaching is teaching is edifying.
>> Same thing. Edifying. Educating. So the
woman go ahead caller
>> and and and the thing about it is uh uh
there ain't nothing said that a woman
can't teach you just read what Joel and
Peter also quoted Joel why he going to
pour out his spirit upon all flesh and
his sons and daughters going to
prophesy. It's just that a woman cannot
hold certain position like running a
church uh religious organization getting
up and teaching being a pastor.
Good. And Paul told you about that. Go
first Corinthians 2 1 Timothy 2 and read
verse 11 and 12.
>> First Timothy 2. Go ahead Tanzel. what
she said.
>> Let the women learn in silence with all
subjection.
But I suffer not a woman to teach, nor
to usurp the authority over the man, but
to be in silence.
>> Now, this is talking about
and in and church, you know, woman uh uh
uh uh you ain't supposed to head up no
congregation. Did you read both verses?
>> Yeah.
Now go to 1 Corinthians the 14th chapter
read verses 34 and 35
>> 1 Corinthians 14
>> Uhhuh.
>> verses 34 and 35.
Let your woman keep silence in the
churches, for it is not permitted unto
them to speak. But they are commanded to
be under obedience, as also said the
law. And if they will learn anything,
let them ask their husbands at home. For
it is a shame for a woman to speak in
the church.
>> You know, now you ain't going to expect
no uh woman to sit in the church and
don't say nothing. But she ain't
supposed to get up and teach. It's all
that simple. But
if a woman somebody say something wrong,
I don't care who he is.
If she know it is wrong and she got
scripture and correct him, correct him.
It's all that simple,
>> sir.
>> Because women can message just is just a
sitting. Otherwise, you wouldn't had you
wouldn't had the uh uh Ruth, which was a
prophetist.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we continue to move on with the time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:22. Andre Jr. asks in
Proverbs 8 26 and 27 is this saying the
father made the earth rather than Jesus.
>> All right. And then Proverbs 8:26 and
27, brother Jerome.
Let's go read it.
>> Proverbs 8:26 27.
While as yet he had not made the earth,
nor the fields, nor the highest parts of
the dust of the world, when he prepared
the heavens, I was there. When he set a
compass upon the face of the depth,
that that's that's talking about the
wisdom that proceeded from the mouth of
Jesus Christ. All right. Um, skip up and
read verse 1-4.
Do not wisdom cry and understanding put
forth her voice? She standeth in the top
of high places, by the way, the places
of the path. She crith at the gate, at
the entry of the city, at the coming in,
at the doors, unto you, oh men I call,
my voice is to the sons of man.
Let's tie that with uh the second
chapter and uh read verse one and two
Proverbs 2.
>> Yeah.
My son, if thou will receive my words
and hide my commandments with thee, so
that thou incline thy ear unto wisdom,
and apply thy heart to understanding.
>> Yeah. Because the the word of God that
coming from the mouth of the Lord is
wisdom and by that wisdom we can get
understanding. Okay. Uh verse six.
For the Lord giveth wisdom. Out of his
mouth cometh knowledge and
understanding.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh one more one more. Um the
third chapter read verse 19.
The Lord by wisdom hath found the earth.
By understanding hath he established the
heavens.
>> And that's what he was really saying in
that uh eighth chapter. Yeah. Yeah. And
there's other places we can go, but I'm
I'mma leave it right there.
>> St. John.
>> Can we go to St. John 1, Rome?
>> Yep. For sure.
>> Let's look at who made the who did all
the creating? St. John through the will
of the father, but who actually did the
creating? St. John 1 and one.
One and one.
>> Yes, sir.
>> In the beginning was the word, and the
word was with God, and the word was God.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The same was in the beginning with God.
All things were made by him, and without
him was not anything made that was made.
>> And that word was Jesus. How do you
know? Read verse 14.
And the word was made flesh and dwelt
among us. And we beheld his glory, the
glory as of the only begotten of the
father, full of grace and truth.
>> And that was Jesus.
>> Yeah. And if if if you come across any
verses that confuse you into thinking
that the father did the creating, no,
the father had Jesus to do the creating.
So could you read that? Ephesians 3
chapter verse 9.
>> Yes sir.
>> Ephesians 3 and9.
>> Yeah.
And be found in him not having my own.
You say Ephesians. My bad. Hold up.
Ephesians 3:9.
and to make all men see what is the
fellowship of the mystery which from the
beginning of the world hath been hid in
God who created all things by Jesus
Christ.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yep. All right. Thank you for that. Hope
that answered your question as we move
on to our next one.
>> Next one. George S says, "King Solomon
built a temple for God, but for who? One
of them or both?"
>> All right. This temple that was built,
who was it built for? Guess. One of
them.
>> It was built for Jesus. Let's go to
Ezekiel the 43rd chapter.
We're going to read one verse one and
two.
We're going to skip down and read verse
4 and 7
1 and two first Ezekiel 43 1 and2.
>> Afterwards he brought me to the gate,
even the gate that lookth toward the
east. And behold, the glory of the God
of Israel came from the way of the east.
And his voice was like a noise of many
waters, and the earth shine with his
glory. Verse
four.
And the glory of the Lord came into the
house by the way of the gate whose
prospect is towards the east.
So the spirit took me up and brought me
into the inner court. And behold, the
glory of the Lord filled the house.
>> Go ahead.
>> And I heard him speaking unto me out of
the house. And the man stood by me, and
he said unto me, Son of man, the place
of my throne, and the place of the souls
of my feet, where where I will dwell in
the midst of the children of Israel
forever, and my holy name shall the
house of Israel no more defile, neither
they nor their kings by their whoredom,
nor by the cartes of their kings in
their high places.
Now the temple that Solomon built
represented this temple
that we that Ezekiel is telling that the
Lord's going to come. And he said, "Son
of man, place of my throne and the place
of the souls of my feet where I will
dwell in midst of the children of Israel
forever." Place of my throne. Whose
throne is that? Let's go into Luke the
first chapter.
We're going to read verses 26 27.
>> Then we're going to skip down to
>> Luke chapter 2 uh first chapter chapter
and verse 26 and 27.
>> In the sixth month, the angel Gabriel
was sent from God unto a city of Galilee
named Nazareth to a virgin espoused to a
man whose name was Joseph of the house
of David. And the virgin's name was
Mary.
>> Now skip down to verse 30 and continue.
>> And the angel said unto her, "Fear not,
Mary, for thou has found favor with God.
And behold, thou shalt conceive in thy
womb, and bring forth a son, and shall
call his name Jesus. He shall be great,
and shall be called the son of the
highest. And the Lord God shall give
unto him the throne of his father David.
Uh-huh.
>> He shall re
go ahead.
>> And he shall reign over the house of
Jacob forever. And of his kingdom there
shall be no end.
>> That's why it said in Ezekiel,
son of man, the place of my throne and
the souls of my feet, where I will dwell
in the midst of the children of Israel
forever. That was talking about Jesus
right
>> now.
Revelation the 20th chapter.
We're going to read verses 4-6.
And I saw throne, and they that sat upon
them, and judgment was given unto them.
And I saw the souls of them that were
beheaded for the witness of Jesus, and
for the word of God, and which had not
worshiped the beast, neither his image,
neither had received his mark upon their
foreheads or in their hands. And they
lived and reigned with Christ a thousand
years. But the rest of the dead live not
again until the thousand years were
finished. This is the first
resurrection.
But blessed holy is he that
>> finish it.
>> Blessed holy is he that hath part in the
first resurrection or such the second
death have no power but they shall be
preached of God and of Christ and shall
reign with him a thousand years.
So now he going to be sitting in his
temple and we going to have people for a
thousand years from there going to be
running this whole earth. Now that's
Jesus kingdom. Now let's bring in the
father's kingdom. Let's go into
Revelation 21st chapter.
We're going to read 1 2 3 and we're
going to skip down
1 to 3.
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth,
for the first heaven and the first earth
were passed away, and there was no more
sea. And I, John, saw the holy city, New
Jerusalem, coming down from God out of
heaven, prepared as a bride adorned for
her husband. And I heard a great voice.
>> Finish it.
out of heaven, saying, "Behold, the
tabernacle of God is with men, and he
will dwell with them, and they shall be
his people, and God himself shall be
with them, and be their God."
>> Amen.
>> Step down.
And he cried and he carried me away in
the spirit to a great and high mountain
and showed me that great city, the holy
Jerusalem, descended out of heaven from
God, having the glory of God and her
light was like unto a stone most
precious, even like a jasper stone clear
as crystal.
>> Now skip down to verse 22 and read it.
And I saw no temple therein, for the
Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the
temple of it. And the city had no need.
>> Now he said that he saw no temple there
in.
So the temple that Solomon built
represent the temple that Jesus going to
rule in
because they saw no temple
in New Jerusalem.
So that's it. The temple represent
Jesus,
not the father.
>> That's all.
>> All right.
>> Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Charles Shanlin asks, "Is it
okay to pray in the bathroom?"
>> Sure is.
Yes, it's a play in the pray.
People like to sit in their bubble baths
or take a shower or
whatever, but you can pray because um
hey, we need God all the time. So,
nothing wrong with praying in the
bathroom and that's all I got.
>> Hey, Cordell.
>> Yeah.
>> Can you hit that Jonah 2 and read verse
one?
>> Oh, yeah.
All right. Let's go to the book of
Jonah.
Jonah 2 and verse one, right after
Oadiah and before Micah.
>> Then Jonah prayed unto the Lord his God
out of the fish the fish belly.
>> Out of the what?
>> Out of the fish belly.
>> Yep. Yeah. And and you know what too?
Sometimes uh Brother Julius uh people
slip and fall sometimes in them
bathrooms. Got to be careful. So hey,
you got to always send up your prayer
when you need God and even when you
don't. But okay,
>> hope that answered your question there
as we continue to move on to our next
one.
>> But the guest caller has something
you can pray anywhere.
>> Yeah, that's right. Anywhere.
All right, let's move on to the next one
with a time check. Deborah,
>> yes, the time is 8:35. 8:36
>> All right.
>> 8:35
Deborah Pasha asks, "When Jesus said,
"Suffer little children to come unto me
and forbid them not."
He was talking about showing them to
come to him for prayer, right? Not for
baptism, which is which is what most
preachers say when baptizing a child.
>> Oh, brother Julius, what you say?
>> I'm looking at the middle of that. He
was talking about following them to come
to him for prayer. Let's go and let's
look at what the Bible say. And this is
what we have to do because it's so easy
to interpret. Let's just stick with what
the book say. Let's go to ma Mark. Mark
the 10th chapter
and we're going to read verse 13- 16.
Mark
10 13- 16.
>> Okay?
>> Cuz Jesus love little children and we
are we are his little children
spiritually speaking. But go ahead and
read.
>> And they brought the young children to
him that he should touch them and his
disciples rebuke those that brought
them. that he should do what to them?
>> Touch them.
>> That he should touch them. Continue.
>> But when Jesus saw it, he was much
displeased and said unto them, "Suffer
the little children to come unto me, and
forbid them not."
>> Uh-huh.
>> Or if such is the kingdom of God.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Very I say unto you, whosoever shall not
receive the kingdom of God as little
child, he shall not enter therein.
>> Uh-huh. So why did he tell uh a lot of
little children to come to me? What? For
what reason? Go ahead.
>> And he took them up in his arms, put his
hand upon them and blessed them.
>> The book said he blessed them.
He blessed them. And as for uh uh
preachers baptizing little children,
what sins have little children done?
Baptism is is for remission of sins and
coming up under the covenant of God.
child don't even know what what he's
done. So, uh all
suffer the little children. Let them
come so I can bless them. That's why the
book say he touched them. Go ahead.
That's all.
>> Somebody back up and see why Jesus made
that statement. [snorts]
>> All right.
for God to join together.
>> When he say suffer little children that
come under me because there's a was a
bit forbidden,
>> right?
>> That's right.
>> What script you guess call her?
>> No, no. The the one that uh
that she
>> the one where it say the little
children.
Yeah. What? What was written before he
said that?
>> We probably have to go up higher than
that.
>> Um,
>> it start talking about divorce and
merit. Is it in probably in another um
maybe he's talking about is
>> Yeah, it's talking about the bill of
divorcement when we talk about
>> is it in Luke 18? Luke 18.
Yeah, that's what I'm looking for.
>> Luke 18. Which one, Dre?
>> Yeah, Luke 18 and uh vers 15 to 17.
>> Yeah.
And they brought unto him also infants,
that he should touch them. But when his
disciples saw it, they rebuked them. But
Jesus called them unto him, and said,
"Suffer little children to come unto me,
and forbid them not. For of such is the
kingdom of God. But verily, I say unto
you, whosoever shall not receive the
kingdom of God as a little child shall
in no wise enter therein."
>> But the real reason he made the
statement is because his apostles was
rebuking him. Didn't want him to blink.
Okay? Right? That is,
>> you know,
>> and so he was telling them to suffer
little children. Suffer the little
children to come unto me. In other
words, you know, uh uh don't forbid
them. That's all,
>> right? Allow them to come.
>> That's that's all he's saying.
>> Nerve of the disciples to rebuke that.
>> And that that's in uh that's in Matthew
19 and 13. what the guest caller said
1913 through 15. So
>> read it
>> Matthew 19.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you, Dre.
>> No doubt.
>> Then go ahead.
>> Start at verse 13.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Then were there brought unto him little
children that he should put his hands on
them and pray. And the disciples rebuked
them. But Jesus said, "Suffer little
children and forbid them not to come
unto me, for of such is the kingdom of
heaven." And he laid his hands on them
and departed then.
>> So that's the reason why he said it. You
know, sometime we get too complicated.
You get away from the question.
That's the answer.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
>> Sir,
>> next one. Love Thrice asks, "Is New
Year's a pagan holiday or just man-made?
Is it okay to celebrate the new calendar
year to come?"
>> All right. Man's world is fast
approaching us. Guess caller.
>> Well, you know, I haven't seen nowhere
in the Bible that says it's a it's
pagan. But if you celebrate new year
then uh uh uh you celebrating the
falsehood
because that is not the new year
>> right
>> the new year is is is not in January it
is in the month a
first month of the year let's go into
Exodus the 12th chapter read verses 1
and two
And the Lord spake unto Moses and Aaron
in the land of Egypt, saying, "This
month shall be unto you the beginning of
months. It shall be the first month of
the year to you."
>> Now that's talking. And let's go to
Exodus the 13th chapter and read verses
3-5 so we can get the name of that
month.
And Moses said unto the people, remember
this day in which ye came out from
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. For
by strength of hand the Lord brought you
out from this place, there shall no
leaven bread be eaten. This day came ye
out in the month. A
>> so now that's the first month of the
year. That's about two and a half or
three months after January.
So now you can celebrate new year but
you're celebrating falsehood. The new is
the year is not new. Same year
>> right
>> come new a bill. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question there as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one. Sean M. D. Holy asks in 2
Corinthians 12:7
in context, was this Paul speaking about
himself?
>> He surely was.
Paul was speaking about himself. But
let's go there, Tanzel, and read this
because Paul,
>> that's second Corinthians uh 12.
>> Yes. Because Paul had an affliction
going on. He went to the Lord and asked
the Lord to remove it. So let's go and
read that.
Second Corinians
12 and pick it up at that verse 7,
brother.
Unless I should be exalted above measure
through the abundance of the
revelations.
There was given to me a thorn in the
flesh, the messenger of Satan to buffet
me as I should exalted above measure.
>> Yep. For this thing I besought the Lord
thrice that it might depart from me. And
he said unto me, "My grace is sufficient
for thee, for my strength is made
perfect in weakness."
>> Yeah.
>> Most gladly therefore will I rather
glory in my infirmities that the power
of Christ may rest upon me.
>> Yep. So yeah, this was Paul talk
speaking
speaking about himself.
>> Guess call
>> said I said just like I was agreeing
with you just like you said he was
speaking of himself.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. All right. So uh Sister Deborah,
can we take a walk in new territory?
>> Uh yes. We are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, December the 31st,
2025.
Zion asks, "Which Africans are our
people?" I've heard people from African
countries in the east like Nigeria.
>> Okay. and ask which Africans are what?
>> Our people?
>> Which Africans are?
>> Which Africas are are are people?
>> Oh, our people. Okay, let's open these
questions up to the panel. Which
>> Africans?
>> None of these none of none of the
Africans is our people. We didn't we
didn't come
um out of the Africans which the Bible
call the people of Ham. You know you the
Africans actually trace the Ham. But the
Israelites they trace back to Shim
>> through uh Yeah. through Abraham and
through Jacob.
>> Yeah. But we you know nine tribes of of
of our people were scattered among the
Africans. Okay. Like for example, if you
were to uh talk about the Nigerians,
our people that's scattered in Nigeria
are called Eboos.
And if you was to go to uh Ethiopia in
Africa, our people there are called
Felasha. They not Ethiopians, they
Israelites. But the
Ethiopian people call our people in
their land felasha. And if you was to go
to Rwanda, which is east, East Africa,
them people, them African people call
our people tootssis cuz you had the
African, the real Africans was killing
our people. They was called the hoou.
them was the real African people and
they was killing our people who were
Israelites but they was referring to
them as the Tootsie. So now we not
Africans but we nine nine tribes of
Israel is scattered among the Africans.
Yeah, that that's all I got to say.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> The the people in Nigeria, the
Israelites call themselves Hebrews.
Uh uh uh but they uh uh
but they are from the uh tribe of Gad.
>> Yeah.
>> And then you got people in Ethiopia
which are called Felashia. Fela means
stranger.
>> They are they are
>> Danites.
>> And you have the some some people in
South Africa. I forgot the name you call
them but anyway they are part of the uh
uh they are part Levi cuz Levi lot of
most Levvis among the Gentiles but some
of them was among them because they was
priest so now you don't know all of them
but one thing oneh
rule the ones that was taken out by
Nebuchadnezzar the Gentiles
among mostly among the Europeans they're
either in America you either Uh, Judah,
Benjamin, or Levi.
>> Levi.
>> Yep.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right. So, I hope that answered your
question there with that good light as
we move on to the next one.
>> Yes. Uh, Zion also asks, "If every
nation can be saved,
what's wrong with dating marrying them?"
If every nation can be saved, what's
wrong with dating them? Let's open that
up to the panel also.
Why don't
>> somebody go read the scripture?
>> All right.
>> Find out what happened. What happened to
Solomon?
>> Like I said, just read the scripture and
see who said what. Who gave the
commandment?
All right, we're in search mode for
that.
>> Still looking.
There's one place in
uh first kings the 11th chapter
when the Lord was telling Solomon
in that second verse.
>> Yeah.
>> Read it.
>> First Kings 11th chapter.
>> Yeah. Verse two.
>> Read it.
>> All right.
Of the nations concerning which the Lord
said unto the children of Israel. Start
at verse one, brother.
But King Solomon loved many strange
women together with the daughter of
Pharaoh, women of the Moabites, the
Ammonites,
the the Zidonians, and the
Hittites,
of the nations concerning which the Lord
said unto the children of Israel, "You
shall not go in to them, neither shall
they come in unto you, for surely they
will turn away your hearts after their
gods." Solomon claimed unto these in
love.
>> Listen. So who told Solomon that?
>> The Lord.
>> Lord
Israel. That
>> huh?
>> The Lord.
>> It's the Lord. Right.
>> The Lord. Yeah. All day long. The Lord.
>> Right. So I think the person that asked
that question should ask the Lord that
soon as they sin.
Okay, we're gonna leave it right there
as we move on to our next question.
>> Uh, next one.
Detroit Price asked for you to break
down Leviticus 25
44- 46.
>> Leviticus 25
44 through 46.
All right, Tanzel, let's go there.
Leviticus 25 and pick it up, brother, at
that 44
46.
>> Yes, sir. Go right ahead. We're going to
open that up to the panel. Go ahead.
>> Both that bond man and that bond made,
but thou shalt have shall be of the
heathen that are round about you. of
them shall ye buy h bond men and bond
mates. But moreover the children of the
stranger that do sjourn among you of
them shall ye by and of their families
that are with you which they begotten
your land and they should and they they
shall be your possession.
>> And you shall take them as an
inheritance for your children after you
to inherit them for possession. and they
shall be your bond men forever. But over
your brethren, the children of Israel,
you shall not rule one over another with
rigor.
>> All right. See, shall not rule over one
another with rigor. No mistreatment.
Go ahead. Um T,
>> that was at that time.
>> Yep.
>> That time is gone.
meant what it said for the time that it
said it.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right, let's move on to our next
one. Deborah, as time is a ticket.
>> Yes. Next one. Be alert as
in Psalms 22
and 16. Could you explain who are the
bulls and dogs that come past Jesus?
>> Let's go to Psalms 22
vers 12 and verse 16.
>> Many bulls have compassed me. Strong
bulls of Bashan have beset me round.
Verse 16, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> The dogs have compassed me. The assembly
of the wicked have enclosed me. They
pierced my hands and my feet.
>> That's the Romans.
>> Yeah. He's just talking about people.
>> The prophecy of Jesus on the cross.
There was Romans that was urged to do it
by Israelites.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah.
>> That's why the chief priests and the
scribes and the elders delivered him up
to the Romans.
>> So it was most Israel than the Romans
because Pilate tried to get him off the
hook
>> and they kept holling. So he so he so
his he got some water and washed his
hand and said my hands
>> clean of the blood of this innocent man.
>> Yep.
>> Them fools and dogs that really
comparison with Israelites.
Yep.
All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on.
>> All right. Moving on. Shanquila Au jobi
says I have a family member who doesn't
believe in Jesus or the Bible and thinks
it was created by whites to control
people. It's hard to ignore their views
since we live together. any scriptures
to help.
>> Why is that you going to ask scripture
>> to read to a person that don't believe
in the Bible?
I call that's an exercise in futility,
>> right?
>> So why should we come up with some
scripture? You don't believe the book
anyway.
>> Yeah.
>> Maybe you should stop talking to him
about it if you don't believe it.
>> Yeah. Because this this Bible was
written by holy men as they were
inspired
by God's holy people, holy ghost of
scripture.
>> Yeah.
>> But he don't believe.
>> So why even discuss it? When a person
tell me they don't believe in the Bible,
I don't I don't talk to them no more
about that.
>> I'd like to give them
>> I'd like for them to get this scripture
though, guest caller, if it's okay for
them. Not for the people that they
that's talking to them. Matthew 7 and6.
Matthew 76. Read that when you get
>> 76.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's that swan. Got that swan.
>> Matthew 76.
>> Read.
Give not that which is holy unto the
dogs. Neither casting your pearls before
swine unless they trample them under
their feet and turned again and ren you.
>> That's it.
>> They don't want to hear trying to feed
it to them. They going to figure out how
to hurt you.
>> Exactly.
>> They swans and dogs don't cancel
before.
>> Yeah. Sad question indeed, Deborah, as
we move on to our next one.
>> All right. Ata Masala asked for you to
explain
not calling anyone father in Matthew 23
verse 9 and 10 and Exodus 20 verse 12.
>> What was that first one? Matthew
>> Matthew 23
9 and 10. And the second one,
>> Exodus 20 verse12
explain not calling anyone father.
>> So that Matthew 23 and pick it up at
that verse 9.
And then the guest caller will shed some
light
>> and call no man your father upon the
earth for one is your father which is in
heaven.
>> Keep reading something else. Keep
reading that a little more.
>> Neither be ye called masters, for one is
your master, even Christ.
>> Go ahead.
>> But he that is greatest among you shall
be your servant.
And whosoever shall
>> go ahead.
>> And whosoever shall exalt himself shall
be abased,
and he that shall humble himself shall
be exalted.
Now go and redirect. Now that is talking
about don't call nobody your physical
father. I mean your spiritual father.
>> Right. Right.
>> You know right around telling these
Catholic priests father
20 years old and you call him father.
>> That's what he's talking about. Don't
call no let nobody call you master. Cuz
the word for master is rabbi. Cuz Jesus
said I am your m. You ain't got a one
master and that's me.
>> Right.
>> So he ain't talking about your B father.
>> He's talking about the one that's
supposed to be your spiritual father.
>> God, you got one father and that's God
that's in heaven. And you got one
master. That's Jesus. But go read the
other piece.
>> Exodus.
>> Exodus 20 and uh 12. That's your
biological father and mother.
read it.
>> Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
>> Like like like uh Julia said, that's
talking about your biological father.
Ain't nothing wrong with calling your
biological father your father,
but you don't call no man your spiritual
father.
Father of Jesus is the father of of our
father. Trust Jesus himself is our
father too. That tell you uh uh uh uh
let's go in that what's it Isaiah where
he said the seventh chapter.
>> Yes sir.
>> All the names he going to be called that
Jesus. Why don't you go seven and and
and see where you can find it started at
>> six. You talking about where it say
counselor the mighty God the everlasting
father. Yep.
>> Hey, unto us a child is born, the son is
given
and six. Yeah.
>> Go ahead.
>> For us, for unto us a child is born.
Unto us a son is given, and the
government shall be upon his shoulders,
and his name shall be called wonderful,
counselor, the mighty God, the
everlasting father, the prince of peace.
>> So now Jesus is our father because
Israel is Jesus' name. He gave us when
when he was adopted. But then we have a
Jesus have a father
which is the father that's all we know
but his name was Jesus because he gave
Jesus his name because Jesus said I come
in my father's name so there are two
type fathers biological father you can
call father but when it come to somebody
that bringing you the word you don't
call them father
spiritual father but god is your father
And in other words, the Lord thought
that you going to have people like the
like the Catholic Church running around
dudes being called father this and
father that.
>> Right.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah. [clears throat] Some
>> Jesus told you in John 5 and 43, I am
come in my father's name.
>> So he got
>> Yeah. Right. And some Yeah. Some kids
have had some some great stepfathers
that they call father as well, but
that's on the on the flesh as we
speaking.
>> As long as it biological, ain't no
problem.
>> All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Uh, the time is 9:02.
>> Oh, 9:02. All right. Well, we have ran
out of time and we want to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in with us and we want to say if
you sent us a question this evening and
we didn't get to it, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah will take
your question and put it in rotation and
we will deal with that next Wednesday.
So, we'd like to thank you all and until
we all come together again, we ask that
you be safe, be blessed, stay prayed up,
and may the Lord have mercy on us all.
As brother Tanzel closes us out.
>> Our Father which art in heaven, hallowed
be thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will
be done in earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.